[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla on today's episode we're going to
be talking about all things AI testing
so we're going to be dipping into things
like uh the context that models are
going to need to be able to create good
tests uh things like evaluation what
does it mean for generated code mod uh
and then look into deeper into AI tests
about when they should be done should
they be done early should be should they
be done late and more automated joining
me today rashab Merra from Source craft
those of you may know Source craft
better as the tool Cody welcome to the
session tell us a little bit about
yourself first of all thanks am this is
really interesting topic for me and so I
work with Source craft we do we've done
like coding code search for for the last
quite a few years and uh I mean we
tackled the big quot problem like if you
look at Enterprises Enterprises have a
lot of developers which is great for
them they also have like massive code
bases look at a bank in the US I mean
they would have like 20 30,000
developers they would have like more
than that like 40,000 repositories right
so this big code problem is a huge pain
right so what what we've done as a
company is like we've spent quite a few
years in tackling code search and then
last year we launched Codi which is a
coding assistant and essentially Codi
lives in your ID it makes tries to make
you a better produ productive developer
and there's a bunch of different
features and my role right now at source
graph is to lead the a effort so I've
done a lot of like machine learning on
the consumer side like looking at
Spotify recommendations music short
video recommendations my PhD was on
search which again ties well because in
llms you need context and we're going to
talk about yeah a lot of that as well
how many years would you say you've been
in
AI yeah so I think the first research
paper I wrote was in 2009 and almost 15
years ago and this was like NLP again
this is not like deep learning NLP this
is more like traditional NLP and I I've
been in the world wherein like the
domain experts handcraft these features
and then embeddings came in and like
they washed all of it away and then
these like neural models came in they
washed like custom topic models away and
then these llms came in and they washed
a bunch of these Rangers away so I think
like I've seen some of these like waves
of if you create like specific models
which are very handcrafted maybe a
simpler large scale like generalizable
model will sweep some of these models
I've seen a few of these waves in lastas
and way before it was cool yeah exactly
I think like I keep saying to a lot of
like early PhD students like in 2010s a
lot of the PhD students would get their
doctorate by just creating latent
variable models and doing some Gip
sampling inference nobody even knows
that 15 years ago this is what would get
you a PhD in machine right so again
things have really moved on you can say
to that you can say you weren't there
you weren't there in the early days
there when you WR gift sampler code and
see we even never hadow P like a bunch
of these I I think like this is I think
like we've seen this is Codi and a lot
of these other gen coding tools they're
trying to make us as developers work at
higher and higher abstractions right I
started my research or ml career not
writing like py code right I wrote again
like Gib sampler in C right and then I'm
not touching C until it's like really
needed now so a lot of these like
Frameworks have come in which have
abstracted the complexities away and
made my life easier and again we're
seeing again I've seen it as an IC over
the last 10 15 years but also that's
also happening in the industry right you
don't have to be bothered by lowlevel
Primitives and you can maybe tackle
higher level things and that's what
exactly Cody is trying to do that how do
I remove toil from your developers life
and then make them focus on the
interesting pieces and the creative
pieces and like really get the
architecture right yeah so let's let's
talk a little bit about some of the
features that you mentioned because
Cody's obviously not it's when we think
about a tool like Cody it's not just
code suggestion there's a ton of
different things and you mentioned some
of them we'll be talking a little bit
more probably about testing today but
when we think about ML and the use of ml
here how does it differ from the various
features that a tool like
does it
when yeah that's an excellent point let
me take a step back right let's not even
talk about coding assist let's go back
to recommendations and let's look at
Spotify or Netflix right people think
that hey if you're doing Spotify is
famous for oh it knows what I want it it
suest nostalgic music for me so people
in in the while love the recommendations
from Spotify I'm not saying this just
because I was an employee at Spotify but
also as a user right I like Spotify
recommendations I have to say Netflix is
there for me like I've never binge
listened anything on Netflix anything on
Spotify but Netflix has kept me up to
the early hours exact questioning my
life yeah I think there a series right
like Netflix for videos you look at
Spotify for music you look at Tik Tok
Instagram me for short videos so again
the mediums are like it used to be hours
of content to like minutes of music to
like seconds of short video but then the
point is we love these products but this
is not just one ranker Netflix is not
just one ranker right it's a bunch of
different features a bunch of surfaces
and user touch points and each touch
point is powered by a different machine
learning model different thinking
different valuation right so my point is
we we this is how the industry has
evolved over the last 10 15 years right
most of these user Centric applications
which people love and like hundreds and
whatever like 400 million users are
using it monthly they are a mix of
different features and each feature
needs a design of what's the ml model
what's the right tradeoffs what are the
right metrics what's the right science
behind it what's the right evaluation
behind it so we have seen this and now
I'm seeing exactly the same at Codi
right if you look at COD so Codi lives
in your ID so if you're a developer if
you're using vs code or jet brains again
if you're writing code then we can code
complete right so aut complete is an
important feature that's like very high
volume right why because it's not that
again right a lot of users use it but
also when you're writing code in a file
you will trigger aut complete like maybe
hundreds of times because you're writing
like one word you're writing like some
syntax in line It'll like trigger and
then if you like what like a ghost text
which is like recommended you can just
Tab and like it selects right yeah so
then it helps you write code in a faster
way now this is I would say that this is
something on the like extreme of hey I
have to be like very latency sensitive
and like really be fast right because
when you're on Google you're rping a
query Google will do like AO suggestions
right itself can I complete your query
so we we've been like using some of
these features for the last decade as
users on the commu site and this is
really important as well because this
interaction that you're just talking
about here it's a very emotive one you
will you will piss people off if you do
not if you do not provide them cuz this
is supposed to be an efficiency play if
you don't provide them with something
that they can actually prove their
workflow and they can just Tab and say
yeah this is so cool I'm tabing tabing
tabing accepting then they're going to
they're going to get annoyed to the
extent that they will almost reject that
kind exactly this is where quality is
important but latency is also important
right so now we see that there's a
trade-off yeah that hey yes I want
quality but then if you're doing it like
400 milliseconds later hey I'm already
annoyed why because the perception of
the user on when they're competing right
they don't want to wait if I have to
wait then i' rather go to code edit or
like chat this is that's a great point
is is latency does latency differ
between the types of things that c
offers or cuz I I would guess if if a
developer is going to wait for something
they might they'll be likely to wait a
similar amount of time across all but
different yeah not really the expect let
me go back to the features right C has
auto complete which helps you complete
code when you're typing out we have code
edit code fix here there's a bug you can
write a command or select something and
say hey Cod fix it yeah now when you're
fixing then people are okay to wait for
a second or two as it figures out and
then they're going to show a diff and oh
I like this change and I'm going to
accept it now this is going to span
maybe 3,000 milliseconds right 3 to 4
seconds yeah versus auto complete no I
want everything tap complete selected
within 400 500 millisecond Laten again
just there the difference start popping
up now we've talked about autocomplete
code edit code fix then we could go to
chat as well right chat is okay I'm
typing inquiry it'll take me like a few
seconds to type in the right query and
select the right code and do this right
so the expectation of 400 milliseconds
is not really the case in chat because
I'm asking maybe a more complex query I
want you to take your time and give the
answer versus like unitest generation
for examp example right unit write the
entire code and make sure that you cover
the right corner cases unit is like
great coverage and like you're not just
missing important stuff you making sure
that the unit is actually quite good now
there I don't want you to complete in 4
in milliseconds take your time write
good code I'm waiting I'm willing to
wait a long time yeah let's take a step
back what what are we looking at we
looking at a few different features now
similar right Netflix Spotify is not
just one recommendation model you go do
search you go do podcast you go do hey I
want this category content a bunch of
these right so similarly here in coding
assistant for COD you have auto complete
code edit code fix unit test generation
you have a bunch of these commands you
have chat chat is an entire nightmare I
can talk about hours on like chat is
like this one box Vision which people
can come with like hundreds of intents
yeah that's e in 10 it's a nightmare for
me as an engineer to say that are we
doing well on that because in aut
complete I can develop metrics around it
I can think about okay this is a unified
this is a specific feature yeah chat may
be like masking hundreds of these
features just by natural language so we
can talk a little more about chat as
well over a period of time but coming
back to the original point you mentioned
for auto complete people will be latency
sensitive yeah for unit generation maybe
less for chat maybe even less what that
means is the design choices which I have
as an ml engineer are different in order
to complete I'm not going to look at
like 400 billion parameter BS right I
ownn something which is f right so if
you look at the x-axis latency Y axis
quality look I don't want to go the top
right top right is high latency and high
quality I don't want latency I want to
be in the like whatever 400 500 n to n
millisecond latency space so there small
models kick in right and small models we
can f tune for great effect right we
we've done some work we' just published
a block post a couple of weeks ago on
hey if you find tune for rust rust is
like a lot more has a lot of nuances
which most of these large language
models are not able to capture so we can
find un a model for rust and do really
well on auto completion within the
latency requirements which we have for
this feature yeah so then these
trade-offs start emerging essentially
how does that change if you if the
output that Cod say was going to provide
the developer would actually be on a
larger scale so we talked when we're
talking about autocomplete we're really
talking about a one liner complete but
what if we was to say I want you to
write this method or I want you to write
this module obviously then you don't
want that you don't want the developer
to accept an autocomplete or look at an
autocomplete module or or function and
think this is absolute nonsense it's
giving me nonsense quickly presumably
then they're willing to they're willing
to wait that much longer yeah I think
there's that's a really good point right
that people use Codi and not just Codi
and not just encoding domain right we
use co-pilots across different I mean
sales co-pilot marketing co-pilot
Finance RIS co- pilot people are using
these agents or assistants in for
various different tasks right and some
of these tasks are like complex and more
sophisticated some of these tasks are
like simpler right yeah so let me let me
just paint this like picture of how I
view this right when you pick up a topic
to learn right beat programming you
don't start with like multi-threading
you start with okay do I know the syntax
can I instantiate variables can I go
fails can I do fall Loop and can I do
switch and then multiread and then
parallelism so when we as humans learn
there is a curriculum we learn on right
we don't directly go to chapter 11 we
start with chapter 1 similarly I think
like the lens which which I view some of
these agents and tools are it's okay you
not at like chapter 12 yet but I know
that there are simpler tasks you can do
and then there are like medium tasks you
can do and then there are like complex
tasks you can do now this is a lens
which is which I found to be like pretty
useful because when you say that hey for
aut complete for example I don't want
again my use case probably for auto
compete is not okay tackle a chapter 12
complexity problem no for that I'll
probably have an agentic setup yeah so
this curriculum is a great way to look
at it the other great way to look at
things are like let's just call it like
left versus right so on the left we have
these tools which are living in your IDE
and they're helping you write better
code and like complete code and like
really you are the main lead you're
driving the car you're just getting some
assistance along the way right versus
things on the right are like agentic
right that hey I'm going to type in here
is my GitHub issue send me create a
bootstrap me a PR for this right there I
want the machine learning models to take
control not full autonomy Quinn our CEO
has a amazing block Post Yeah on levels
of code right you start level Zer to
level seven and some of these human
initiated AI initiated AI Le and that
gives us a spectrum to look at autonomy
from a coding assistant perspective
which is great I think everybody should
look at it but coming back to the
question auto complete is probably for
I'm still the lead driver here help me
but in some of the other cases I'm stuck
take your time but then tackle more
complex task yeah now the context and
the model size the the latencies all of
these start differing here right when
you're writing this code you probably
need for a to complete local context
right or like maybe if you're
referencing a code from some of
repository bring that as a dependency
code and then use it in context if
you're looking at a new file generation
or like a new function generation that's
okay you got to look at the entire
repository and not just make one changes
over here you have to make an entire
file and make changes across three other
files right M so even where is the
impact the impact in auto it is like
local in this file in this region right
and then if you look at the full
autonomy case or like agentic setups
then the impact is okay I'm going to
make five changes across three files
into two repositories yeah right so
that's that's the granularity at which
some of these things are starting to
operate essentially yeah and testing is
going to be very simp similar as well
right if someone is if someone's writing
code in the in their ID line by line and
that's maybe using a code generation as
well like Cody they're going to likely
want to be able to have test step step
in sync so as I write code you're
automatically generating tests that are
effectively providing me with that
assurance that that the automatically
generated code is working as I want to
yeah that's a great point I think this
is more like errors multiply yeah if I'm
evaluating something after long writing
it then it's worse off right because the
errors I could have stopped the errors
earlier on and then debugged it and
fixed it locally and then moved on so
especially so taking a step back look I
love evaluation I really in machine
learning I I started my PhD thinking
that hey mats and like fancy graphical
models are the way to have impact using
machine learning right and you spend one
year in the industry realized nah it's
not about the fancy model it's about do
you have an evaluation you have these
metrics do you know when something is
working better yeah so I think getting
the zero to one on evaluation on these
data sets that is really key for any
machine learning problem y now
especially when what you mean by the
zero to one yeah 0 to1 is look at like
whenever a new language model gets
launched right people are saying that
hey for coding M Lama 3 does well on
coding why because oh we have this human
eval data set and a passet one metric
let's unpack that human eval data set is
a data set of 164 questions hey write me
a binary search in this code right so
essentially it's like you get a text and
you write a function and then you're
like hey does this function run
correctly so they have a unit test for
that and if it passes then you get plus
one right yeah so now this is great it's
a great start but is it really how
people are using Cod and a bunch of
other coding tools no they're like if
I'm an Enterprise developer if if let's
say I'm in a big bank then I have 20,000
other peers and there are like 30,000
depositories but I not writing binary
search independent of everything else
right I'm working in a massive code base
which has been edited across the last 10
years and there's some dependency by
some team in Beijing and there's a
function which I haven't even read right
and maybe it's in a language I don't
even care about or understand so my
point is the evaluation which we need
for these Real World products is
different than the benchmarks which we
have in the industry right now the one
for evaluation is that hey sure let's
use passet one in human at the start on
Day Zero but then we see that you
improve it by 10% we have results when
we actually did improve pass it one by
10 15% we tried it online on COD users
and the metrics dropped yeah and we
writing a block post about it at offline
online correlation yeah because if you
trust your offline metric pass it one
you improve it you hope that hey amazing
users are going to love it yeah it
wasn't true the context is so different
yeah the context are so different now
this is this means that I got to develop
an evaluation for my feature and I got
my evaluation should represent how my
actual users using this feature feel
about it m just because it's better on a
metric which is an industry Benchmark
doesn't mean that improving it will
improve actual user experience and can
that change from user to user as well so
you mention a bank there if five other
Banks is it going to be the same for
them if something not in the fin Tech
space is it going to be different for
them that's a great point I think the
Nuance you're trying to say is that hey
one are you even feature aware in your
evaluation because passet one is not
featur away right yeah passet one
doesn't care about auto complete or
unitize generation or code fixing I
don't care what the end use case or
application is this is just evaluation
so I think the first jump is have an
evaluation data set which is about your
feature right the evaluation data set
for unit as generation is going to be
different that code completion it's
going to be different than code edits
it's going to be different than chat so
I think the 0 to one we talking about 5
minutes earlier you got to do 0 to ones
for each of these features yeah and
that's not easy because evaluation
doesn't come naturally yeah and once you
have it then the question becomes that
hey okay once I have it for my feuture
then hey can I reuse it across
Industries can I reuse it across like
users and I think we've seen it I've
seen it in the rec traditional
recommendation space let's say most of
these apps again if they got like seed
funding last year or maybe series a
there at what like 10,000 daily active
users 5,000 daily active users today one
year from now they're going to be 100K
500k daily active users right now how
representative is your subset of users
today right the 5,000 users today are
probably early adopters and if anything
is scaling companies in the last 10
years what it has told us is the early
adopters are probably not the
representative set of users you'll have
once you have a mature adoption yeah
what that means is the the metrics which
are develop and the learnings which I've
had from the initial AB test may not
hold one year down the line six months
down the line as in when the users start
increasing right yeah now how does it
link to the point you asked look there
are heterogeneities across different
domains different Industries luckily
there are like homogeneities across
language right if you're a front-end
developer a versus B versus C companies
a lot of the tasks you're trying to do
are like similar and a lot of the task
which the pre-training data set has seen
is also similar because rarely again
there are cases where you're doing
something really novel but a lot of the
junior development workflow probably is
more like things which like hundreds and
thousands of Engineers have done before
so the pre-trained models have seen this
before right so when we finding the mod
for us that's not where we saw
advantages because yeah you've seen it
before you're going to do it well MH
coming back to the point I mentioned
earlier it's going to be a curriculum
right you can do simple things well you
can do harder things in Python well you
can't do harder things in Rust well you
can't do harder things in MA lab well so
my goal of fine-tuning some of these
models is that hey I'm going to show you
examples of these hard task not because
I just want to play with it but because
some of our adopters right some we have
a lot of Enterprise customers using us
right and paying us for that right I get
my salary because of that essentially so
essentially I want those developers to
be productive and they're trying to
tackle some complex tasks in Rust which
maybe we haven't paid attention when we
were training this llama model or like
this entropic model so then my goal is
how do I extract those examples and then
bring it to my Loop training Loop
essentially and that's where right now
if let's say one industry is struggling
we know how the metrics are performing
right that's what evaluation is so
important we know where we suck at right
now and then we can start collecting
public examples and start focusing the
models to do well on those right yeah
again let me bring the exact point I
mentioned I I'm going to say it 100
times we've done it before if you spend
20 minutes on Tik Tok you're going to
look at what 40 short videos If you
spend 5 minutes on Tik Tok or Instagram
re you're going to look at like 10 short
videos right yeah in the first nine
short videos you're going to either skip
it or like it or follow a Creator do
something right so the 11 short perod is
like really personalized because I've
seen what you're doing in the last 5
minutes and I can do real-time
personalization for you yeah what does
that mean in the coding assistant world
look I know how these models are used in
the industry right now and how our
Enterprise customers and our community
users are using it yeah let's look at
the ACC completion acceptance rate or
autocomplete oh for these languages in
these use cases we get a high acceptance
rate we show our recommendation
people accept the code and move on but
in these on examples oh we're not really
doing well so the question that me comes
oh this is something which maybe we
should train on or we should find you on
and this establishes a feedback loop
yeah that look at what's not working and
then make the model look at more of
those examples and create that feedback
loop which can then make the models
evolve over a period of time and so I
think there's two pieces here if we move
a little bit into the into what this
then means for testing the more that
evaluation like almost like testing of
the model effectively gets better it
effectively means that the suggested
code is then more accurate as a result
the you need to rely on your tests
slightly less I'm not saying you
shouldn't but slightly less because the
generated code that is being suggested
is a higher quality when it then comes
to the suggestions of tests afterwards
does that follow the same model in terms
of learning from not just the what the
user wants to test but also from what is
being generated
is there work that we can do there into
building that test yeah I think that's
an interesting point generation is a
selfcontained problem in itself right
yeah one I think let's just establish
the fact that unit generation is
probably one of the highest value use
cases yeah we got to get right in the
industry code and that's because I
mentioned that look you will stop using
spotify if I start showing shitty
recommendations to you yeah if I don't
learn from my mistakes you're going to
keep skipping like short videos or music
or podcast and you're going to go right
I don't get value because I spend I'm
running I'm jogging I want music to just
come in and I don't want to stop my
running and hit like skip because that's
takes that's like dissatisfaction right
yeah one of the things which I did at
Spotify and like in my previous company
was like I really wanted people to focus
on dissatisfaction yeah because
satisfaction is all users are happy yeah
that's not where I make more money I
make more money by reducing
dissatisfaction where are you unhappy
and how do I fix that and even there if
I stop you there actually just quickly I
think there are different levels to this
as well in terms of the testing right
cuz it's at some point it's yes at its
most basic does this code work and then
as it goes up it's does this code work
well does this code work fast does this
code is this really making you happy as
a user and so I think where would you
say we are right now in terms of the
level of test generation are people most
concerned with the this code is being
generated or when I start creating my
tests how do I validate that my code is
correct in terms of it compiles it's
it's covering my basic use cases that
I'm asking for and doing the right thing
no this we can talk an hour about this
look I think this is a long journey yeah
getting evaluation getting United
generation right across the actual
representative use case in the
Enterprise that's a nightmare of a
problem yeah look I can do it right for
writing binary binary search algorithms
right if you give me like if you give me
a coding task which has nothing to do
with a big code repository and like
understanding context understanding what
the 5,000 developers have done sure I
can attempt it and create a unit test
because this there's a code and there's
a unit T this lives independently right
they live on an island they're happily
married amazing everything works but
this is not how people use coding this
is not how like the Enterprise or like
even Pro developer use cases are the pro
developer use cases are about like hey
is this working correctly in this like
wider context because there's a big code
repository and like multiple of them and
that's a wider context wherein you're
actually writing the code and you're
actually writing the unit test now I
would bring in this philosophical
argument of I think unit generation I
would look at it from an a Serial
setting what's the point of having the
unit test it's not just to feel make
your yourself or your manager happy that
oh I have unitest coverage unit test are
probably like a guard rail to keep bad
code from entering your system yes so
what is this this is an adversarial
setup maybe not intentionally
adversarial aders set up okay somebody's
trying to make bad things happen in your
code and somebody else is stopping that
from happening right so again if you
start looking at unitest generation from
this adversar setup that look this is a
good guy right the unitest is going to
prevent bad things from happening in
future to my code base that's why I need
good unit test now this bad now this is
a good guy right who are the bad people
right now in the last up until the last
few years the bad people not
intentionally bad but the Bad actors in
The Code base were developers yeah now
we have ai yeah right now I am as a
developer writing code and if I write
shitty code then the unitest will catch
it and I won't be able to merge yeah
right if
ifel right exactly we'll get to that
right I'm yet to I'm yet to see a
developer who who is not a tdd fan who
absolutely lives for writing tests and
building a perfect test s for the code
yeah yeah again right and there's a
reason why quot like test case coverage
like low across like all the
repositories up right it's not something
which again I think like biang CTO he
loves to say that the goal of cod is to
remove developer toil yeah and how do I
make you do a lot more happier job
focusing on the right creative aspects
of architecture design or system design
and remove toil from your life right a
bunch of Developers for for better RSE
to start looking at unit as generation
as maybe it's not as interesting let's
unpack that as well not all unit tests
are like boring right yeah writing
stupid unit test for stupid functions we
shouldn't even like probably do it or
like I I will let like machine learning
do it essentially but the Nuance are
like here is a very critical function if
you screw this then maybe the payment
system in your application gets screwed
and then you lose money right and then
you don't if you don't have
observability then you lose money over a
period of time and then you're literally
costing company dollars millions of
dollars if you screw this code
essentially so the point is not all unit
tests are the same because not all
functions are equally important right
there's going to be a distribution of
some of the are like really really
important functions you got to get a
amazing unit test right I would rather I
if I have a limited budget that if I
have to principal Engineers I would make
sure that the unit of these really
critical pieces of component in my
software stack are written by these
Engineers or even if they written by
like these agents or AI Solutions then
at least like they wed it from some of
these MH but before we get there let's
just look at the fact of the need for
unit test not just today but tomorrow
yeah because right now if you have
primarily developers writing unit test
or like some starting tools tomorrow a
lot more AI assistant I mean we are
building one right we are trying to say
that hey we're going to write more and
more of your code yeah what that means
is if in the adversarial setup unit test
are like protecting your code base the
the potential attacks not intentional
but the bad code could come in from
humans but also like thousands and
millions of AI agents tomorrow yeah and
you know what worries me a little bit
here as well is in fact when you talked
about that that those levels autonomy on
the far left it's much more interactive
right you have developers who are
looking at the lines of code that
suggested and looking at the tests that
get generated so it's much more involved
for the developer as soon as you go
further right into that more automated
World we're we're more in an we're more
in an environment where um larger
amounts of content is going to be
suggested to that developer and if we go
back to the same old that story where if
you want 100 comments on your PO request
in a code review you write two line
change if you want zero you provide a
500 line change right and when we
provide that volume whether it's hey I'm
going to build you this part of an
application or a module or a test Suite
based on some code how much is a
developer actually going to look in
detail at every single one of those
right and I think this kind of comes
back to your point of what are the most
important parts that I need to to look
at but yeah it revolves a little bit
more around what you were saying earlier
as well whereby tests becoming more more
important for this kind of thing and
exactly as code gets generated
particularly in volume right what are
where are the guard rails for this and
it's all about tests I love the point
you mentioned right that look as more
and more code gets written like my the
cognitive abilities of a developer to
look at every change everywhere it just
takes more time takes more effort takes
more cognitive load right yeah now
coupling the fact that if you've been
using this system for a few months then
there's an inherent trust in the system
now this is when I get really scared you
look at
when I started using Alexa in 2015 right
it would only get weather right right
Google home Alexa it won't do any of
other who can get weather
right yeah weather prediction is a hard
enough maching problem Deep Mind
Engineers are still working on it and
still getting it right and doing it in
London yeah I would pay for a service
which predict but point is we have used
as a society like these conversational
agents for a decade now we just asking
like crappy questions yeah because we
trust it I asked you a complex question
you don't have an answer I I forgot
about you for the next few months but
but then we start increasing the
complexity of the questions we ask and
that's great because now the the Siri
and the and the Google assistant and
Alexa was able to tackle these questions
right and then you start trusting them
because hey oh I've asked you these
questions and we've answered them well
so then I trust you to do these tasks
well and again right if you look at
people who use Spotify or Netflix their
recommendations in the feed they have
more Trust on your system yeah because
most of these applications do provide
you a way out right if you don't trust
recommendations go to your library go do
search yeah search search versus
recommendations is that push versus pull
Paradigm right recommendations I'm going
to push content to you if you trust us
you're going to consume this right if
you don't trust a system if you don't
trust your recommendations then you're
going to pull content which is search
right now especially as in when you seen
there's a distribution of people who
don't search at all right they're like
they we live in that high trust world
when they're going to they're going to
like like a recommendation same right
Google who goes through the second page
of Google right who goes through Google
now sorry uh but essentially the point
is once people start trusting these
systems
the units generation is a system which I
start trusting right and then it starts
tackling more and more complex problems
and then is oh I start I stopped looking
at the corner cases and then that code
was committed 6 months ago and that unit
T is there and then code on top of it
was committed three months ago and then
there's probably unit test which I
didn't write the agent road now this is
where like complexity evolves for a
period of time and maybe there's a
generation of unit test which have been
written maybe with less and less of me
being involved yeah the the levels of
code a like that means like your
involvement is not at the finer levels
it's like higher up now this assumes it
works well if the foundations are
correct and everything is robust and we
have like good checks in place yeah
again right whatever could go wrong
would go wrong yeah so then the point is
in this complex code where in the series
generations of unit test generations of
code Cycles edits have been made by an
agent then things could go horribly
wrong so do we have what's the solution
the solution is pay more respect to
evaluation right look you got to you got
to LD is guard is just like a very
harmless way to for me to say that like
unitz generation is important not just
for unit generation today but for unit
generation and code generation tomorrow
so I think like the kind of metrics we
need the kind of evaluation we need the
kind of robust auditing of these systems
and auditing of these unites so far
again I don't have a huge 10e experience
in the coding industry because I've
worked on recommendations and use C
systems for but for me it was like hey
what is your test coverage in a
repository that's the most commonly way
look way to look at like repository and
what's what I how advanced are you in
your testing capabilities and that
doesn't cut it are you covering the con
cases what's your again what's the
complexity what's the severity so do we
need automated tests for our tests or do
we need people humans to we need both
right we need human domain experts again
this is and this is not just a coding
problem look at look millions of dollars
are spent by entropic and open mind on
scale AI scale AI has they raised like a
lot of money recently billion dollar
valuations because we need domain
experts to tag yeah this is also
nightmare at Spotify in search I have PD
in search my search was like I'll show
users some results and they're going to
tag this is correct or not I can't do
this in coding MH because crowdsourcing
has been a great assistance to machine
learning systems for 20 years now
because I can get that feedback from the
user now to get feedback on a complex
rust code where am I going to find those
crowdsource workers on scale or Amazon
Mt right they don't exist you're not
going to pay them $20 an hour to write
give feedback they're like, hour dollar
what ,000 hour developers right yeah we
don't even have a community right now
around around crowdsource workers for
code because this is domain specific
right so my point is again this is not
all Dooms worthy in the sense like this
is a important problem we we got to get
righted uh and it's going to be a long
journey we're going to do evaluations
and we're going to do like generations
of evaluations I think the right way to
think about is like paying attention to
unit test but also like evaluation of
unit test and also evaluation take a
step back like multiple lels of
evaluation right you're going to
evaluate okay what are the important fun
are we able to write identify the
important functions the criticality of
the code right and then look at unit as
generation from that lens yeah now
immediately one of the solutions I think
when we met over coffee we talking
briefly about it if let's say I generate
20 unit test right now I want my
principal or some respected trusted
engineer to wet at least some of them
now their day job is not just to write
unit test right their day job is to
maintain the system advance wants it so
they're going to probably have limited
budget to look at the unit I've
generated right now the question becomes
if this week I was able to generate 120
unit test and you are a principal
engineer in my team you're not going to
look at 120 unit tests and pass them MH
you maybe have two hours to spare this
week yeah you're going to look at maybe
five of these unit test yeah now this
becomes an interesting machine learning
problem for me yeah the 120 unit test
I've created which what is a subset of
five which I need your input on yeah now
this is
one way to tackle these problems reduce
the uncertainity right machine learning
uncertainity models we've done it for 20
years in the industry so likey how
certain am I that this is correct and if
I'm certain then sure I I won't show it
to you yeah maybe I'll show one off just
to make sure that I I get a feedback
that I thought I'm certain you did you
confirm or did you reject that and then
I'll learn but then I'm I'm going to go
on an information maximization principle
that what do I not know and can I show
that to you mhm uh so what that means is
it's a budget constrained subset
selection problem mhm right that I've
generated 120 unit test you can only
look at five of them I'm going to pick
up these five and see now we can do it
like I I can pick up these five and show
it to you or I can pick up one get that
feedback see what I additionally learn
from that one and then look at the 119
again and say that knowing what I know
just now what else would I say what is
the next one yeah and previously you
mentioned about the most important parts
of the code to test right cuz there
could be critical paths there could be
other areas where you know what if
there's a bug it's far less of a problem
who provid that context is that
something the is that something the LM
can like decide or is that something
like you said the principal Engineers
should spend a little bit of their time
saying look these are the main core
areas that we need to be bulletproof
right other areas yeah I would rather
spend my time on these than those others
yeah I think I probably am not the best
person to answer like who currently
provides it as a machine learning
engineer I see there are signals yeah if
I look at your system then there are
like where is the bugs race where was
the severity right for each bug for each
incident there was a severity report
watch code what code was missed what
code wasn't missed yeah what were the
unit tests created by people so far
right so again I view it from a data
observability perspective like knowing
what I know about your code about your
severity about your issues about your
time to resolve some of these then I can
develop a model personalized to your
code base on what are the core important
pieces right so I can look at just code
which okay which functions are calling
which there's a dependency and we do a
lot of we have amazing Engineers right
on who are just like compiler experts in
the company
and one of the Reas join was because
bring in the ml knowledge but I want to
work with dom experts right and has
amazing talent over the last few years
and it compiles it compounds right so
there are these compilers experts
internally Olaf and a few others being
one of them and they would do like
really like precise Intelligence on the
code and find out the dependency
structure and all those right and that
will give me like just content
understanding of your code base right
and then if a function is deemed
important from those like graphical
links essentially like how many of
inotes and out notes are coming to your
do your function and a lot of people are
calling it then that means there's a lot
of Downstream dependencies so there is
this way of looking at it right now this
is just pure code but I do have
observational data observational data
means that I do know what were the
severities and where the SE zeros and SE
1es were cost and where the red really
critical errors have happened the last
few months ni and where is the
probability of those happening right now
plus where are you writing unit test
right now that gives me an additional
layer of information I already have
passed your code base understood what's
going on I have that view but I also now
look at the real world view of that data
coming in oh you know what there was a
depend there was a SE zero issue caused
by this piece of code over here and
maybe this that that meant now the
question is can I go back one day before
yeah can I predict that this is if I had
to pred that one error is going to pop
up tomorrow which part of the code base
where this error will be will be popping
up right now that is a prediction I can
make one day before right and I can
start trading these models now now this
is again we talked about earlier right
at the start of the podcast that look
each of these features are different ml
models right we just talked about two ml
models one if I have 120 unit test what
is the subset of five I've showed you
that could be an llm that could be like
a subset selection subset selection have
known solutions for I mean and like
theoretical guarantees on performance
submod submod subset selection and all
I've implemented them at 200 million
monthly active user scale at Spotify
yeah so we can tackle this problem but
this is a new problem this is not like
an llm solution right second one is here
right can I predict where the critical
bug is going to be and then use that to
identify critical components and then
use that to chain and put like a unius
in there it's essentially human context
right we we we talk about context a lot
when we talking about actual source
source files and and how we can maybe do
some code completion against so many
parts of our project but thinking about
that almost behavioral context exactly
and again I'll be literally like the
broken record on this we have done this
before and look when you upload a short
video like I look at Short video has
zero views right now I look at hey is
this high quality who's the author again
right I look at the content composition
why because zero people have interacted
with it so far give it an hour 10
million people would have interacted
with that short video now I know which
people will like which people not right
so if you look at the recommendation
life cycle of any podcast we're going to
upload this podcast the life cycle of
this podcast will be there is something
about the content of this podcast and
there's something about the
observational behavioral data of this
podcast which developers which users
liked it and not liked it skipped it
streamed it and all that right so we
have designed recommendation systems
as a combination of like content and
behavior right same here when I say uni
as Generations I can look at your code
base right and I can make some
inferences now on top of that I have
additional view on this data which is
like what are the errors and where are
the you writing unit is where are you
devoting time that gives me additional
observation data on top of my content
understanding if a code base combine the
two together and like better things will
emerge Essen and we've talked about unit
tests quite a bit in terms of testing in
general right there are obviously
different layers of of that testing I
think when we talk about the intent
changes heavily right so the higher you
go when we talking about the integration
test and things like that the intent is
really and again when we talk go back to
context the intent is about the use
cases uh a lot about the the intention
of what a user will how a user will use
that application um when we also think
about the the areas of the codebase
which are extremely important those
higher level integration tests the flows
that they go through through the
application will show which areas of
code are most important as well in terms
of from our developer audience when
people we talk to when we want to
provide advice or best practices in
terms of how should a developer be
thinking about using AI into their
General testing strategy what's a good
start today would you say in terms of
introducing these kind of Technologies
into people's processes and existing
workflows successfully today right yeah
I think the the simplest answer is start
using Cody uh no I love it I think like
I even before I joined SCE craft Cody
helped me I interviewed basically Cody
Source craft we do an interview of okay
here's a code base it's open source look
at it try to make some changes and I
love that I psychologically I was bought
in even before I had an offer because
you're making me do cognitive word on
your code depository as part of the
interview you just spend one hour
instead of just chatting look at the
code and make some changes right yeah my
point is yeah use cod but essentially an
interesting point over here is if you're
trying to adopt Cod or any of the other
tools for test generation you're going
to what what are you going to do you're
going to try to use the off thes shell
feature right hey generate unit I see
where it works where it doesn't work now
Cod provides something called custom
commands custom command edit code unit
generation these are all commands right
what a command is if what is the llm
feature let's just take a step back llm
feature is I want to do this task I need
some context so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to generate an English prompt
right and I'm going to bring in a
context strategy that what are the
relevant pieces of information I should
use which is okay here's the unit is in
the same folder for example or here's a
dependency which you should be aware of
bring in that context write an English
prompt and then send to the llm right
that's a very nice simplified way of
looking at what is an llm feature so Cod
provides an option of doing custom
commands what that means is I can see
hey this doesn't work as great for me
why because of these Nu aners let me
create a custom command now you are a
staff engineer at this company you can
create a custom command and that oh this
is better now because in an Enterprise
setting you can now share this custom
command with all your employees
essentially right you said that hey you
know what this is a better way of using
the unit generation because I've created
this custom command and everybody can
benefit essentially right mhm now what
makes you write a better custom command
and even if you forget about custom
commands and cod what makes you get a
better output out this is where the 0
to1 evaluation comes in like where are
you currently failing what sort of unit
test are we getting right what sort of
are we not getting it right what about
this is interesting right what about
your code base is interesting now the
question then becomes can I provide that
as context so can I provide can I track
that that where are we where is it
failing where is it not faing and then
there are few interventions you could do
right you can change the prom new custom
con or you can create a new context
Source now this is a great Segway for me
to just mention one thing which is open
context so I think Quin Rio he literally
started his work as an IC one of the
other impressing things about Source
graph is you look at the you look at the
GitHub history commit histories of the
founders are they running a company or
are they likeing up these things and it
just blew me away like when I first got
it came across that but essentially
Quinn introduced and then a lot of the
teams worked on it something called open
context yeah which is internet
Enterprise setting you have so much
context which we may not be nobody can
get right right yeah because you're
going to plug in thousands of different
heterogeneous context sources is going
to help you get a better answer so open
context is a protocol designed to add
you can add a new context source for
yourself and there's a protocol and cod
will cod and even the other because it's
a protocol a lot of the other agents or
Tools around can use so essentially what
that means is if you are writing unit
test and if you know that this is where
it's not working you're going to make a
change in the prompt add a custom
command you're going to add some other
examples and then you're like hey maybe
I should add a context Source because oh
I have this information like we talked
about right where are the errors coming
in from now that S zero is probably not
something which you have given access to
Cod right now but then because of the
open context open CTX you can add this
like context source and then make your
Solutions better right yeah what are you
doing here you're doing this you're
doing like ml applied machine learning
101 now for your feature right so again
this is exactly where you need like a 0
to one five examples where it doesn't
work right now and if you make the St
change or context change it's going to
start working right so you have done
this mini z to one for your own goal
right and I think there's a meta point
over here which is forget about coding
assistants I think we're all
transitioning to that abstraction of
working with an ml system working with
an AE AI system I hate to use the phrase
AI I I from the machine learning world I
rather say machine learning but again
the audiences probably buy that more
some of the audiences but essentially a
lot of us are starting to work with
systems and I think the way we start
interacting with them are going to be
like a bit more orchestrated right try
this let's figure out where it's working
great I'm going to use it let's figure
out where it's not working okay cool
then I'm going to either give that
feedback or do something and adjust my
workflow a bit and then make it work
better on those right yeah so I think we
all starting to be that applied
scientist one right in some way or the
other and this is not just like you as
an engineer if you're a domain expert if
you're a risk analyst you want to create
these plots or if you're a sales assist
using a sales Scope Pilot you are
working with an agentic setup of ML and
you want to see where it's working where
it's not and what changes do I want to
make again you have done it when you add
Like A Plus or double quotes in Google
you get those words right what is that
you're adopting right you know where
what's going to work you're going to
start adding those tricks and now
because more and more of your daily
workflow is going to be around these
agents and systems and you start
developing these feedback loops yourself
so I think like what we are trying to do
as mlus in the proc product are is
similar philosophically to what you are
trying to do to use these products
essentially so I think like I would a
lot of my friends and other people ask
me like hey like what's happening like
I'm a doain expert I was in another
panel a few days ago versus employees
and the question there was like jobs and
all those right again not to bombard the
conversation around those but
essentially if we start acting as
orchestrators of these systems then we
start developing intuitions on where
it's working where it's not and then we
start putting in these guardrails yeah
and those guardrails are going to help
in uni as your Miss and and I think
that's important because as our audience
are all going to be somewhere on that
Journey from it being fully interactive
to it being fully automated and people
are going to maybe want to be somewhere
on that Journey but they will progress
from one end to the other of that as we
get into that more and more automated
space I remember you saying earlier when
we talk about the budget of a human in
terms of they have an amount of time if
you have 120 tests you want to provide
them with five how do you place the
importance of a developer's time right
in the future when things get to that
more automated State how would you place
that that relevance on a developer
focusing on code versus focusing on
testing versus focusing on something
else where is it most valuable to have
that developers eyes yeah so I think
let's take a step back right you're a
developer I'm a developer and there's a
reason I have a job right I have a job
to do that job means there's a task to
complete right the reason why I'm
writing this unit test I don't get paid
money just to write a better unit list
right I get paid money to again not me
specifically in my job but essentially
as a developer I get paid money if I can
do that task and if I can at least spend
some time in making sure that in
future my load of doing that task is
easier and the system is like helping me
down the scam with that high level view
right the what's happening what's
happening is rather than focusing on
unitized generation or like code
completion as a I care about this
because I care about the silo no I care
about this because I care about the task
being completed and I can if I can do
this task 10 next quicker then what's my
path from today spending 5 hours doing
it to 20 minutes doing it right and this
is where I mentioned you're going to be
we're all going to be orchestrators
right look at the music orchestra right
you have the symphony and you're there's
an orchestra and like you're hand waving
your way into amazing music right art
gets created right again that that's the
goal right Cody wants to make sure that
we allow users developers to start
creating art and not just toil now I I
can say this English right but then I
think a good developer would just embi
the spirit of it which is that look my
role is the sooner I can get to that
orchestrator role in my mindset the more
I start using these tools exactly right
rather than being scared of oh it's
writing code and I won't again you
mentioned right there's going to be like
you might want to be somewhere on that
Spectrum but the the Evol technological
Evolution will march on and we're going
to be forced into some parts and it
could be not just technology but
individuals wanting to be individuals
love writing code or
it's like that will need to change
depending on where what technology
offers us but I guess what's the if we
push further to that right what's the
highest risk right to what we're
delivering not being the right solution
is it is it is it testing now is it
guard rails that become the most
important thing and almost I would say
more important than code or or or is
still code the thing that that we need
to care about the most yeah I think like
if I view this extreme of like again if
I put my evaluation heart right I think
I want to be one of the most prominent
prop proponent vocal proponent of
evaluation in the industry not just cod
in the machine learning industry we
should do more
evaluation so there I would say that
writing a good evaluation is more
important than writing a good model yeah
important than writing a better context
Source because you don't know what
what's a better Contex Source if you
don't have a way to evaluate it right so
I think for me evaluation precedes any
feature development yeah if you don't
have a way to evaluate it then you don't
you're just shooting darts in the dark
room right some are going to land by
luck now there in that world right I
have to ensure that unit test and
evaluation is like ahead in terms of
importance and just like code that said
I I think overall right what's more
important is like task success right
which is again what is Task success
you're not just looking at unit test as
an evaluation you're looking at
evaluation of the overall goal which is
hey do I do this task F and then I think
if that's where as an orchestrator if I
start treating these agents could be Cod
Auto compete or like like any specific
Standalone agent powered by Source graph
as well probably so in those words
evaluation of that task because you are
the Roman expert assume AGI exists today
assume the the foundation models are
going to get smarter smarter like
billions of dollars trillions of dollars
eventually into it we train these fan
again the smartest models and they can
do everything but you are best place to
understand your domain on what the goal
is right now right so you are the only
person who can develop that evaluation
of like how do I know that you're
correct how do I know whether you're 90%
correct 92% correct and again right the
marginal gain on 92 to 94 is going to be
a lot more harder than going from to 90
right it always gets saer like I mean
there's going to be like an exponential
hardness increase over there so
essentially the point then becomes
purely on evaluation purely on unit test
right what makes us what are the nuances
of this problem of this domain which the
model needs to get proved and are you
are we able to articulate those and are
we able to generate those unit test so
generate those guard RS and evaluations
so that I can judge how the models are
getting better on that topic right so
the models are going to be far
intelligent cre but then what is Suess
you as a domain expert get to Define
that and this is a great thing not just
about coding but also like any domain
expert using machine learning or these
tools across domains you know what
you're using it for right the other AGI
tools are just tools to help you do that
job so you it's I think the owners is on
you to write good evaluation or I mean
maybe tomorrow llm as a judge and like
people are developing Foundation models
just for evaluation right so there going
to be other tools to help you do that as
well code Foundation models for like
unitest maybe that's the thing in 6
months from now right uh the point then
becomes what should it focus on that's
the role you're playing orchestrating
but like orchestrating on the evaluation
oh did you get that corner piece right
or you know what this is a criticality
of the system right the again right the
payment Gateway link and the
authentication link some of these get
screwed up then massive bad things
happen right so you know that so I think
that's where like the human in the loop
and your input to the system starts
getting amazing rashab we could talk for
hours on this I know this has been
really interesting and I love the Deep
dive like a little bit below into the ml
space as well I'm sure a lot of our
audience will find this very interesting
thank you so much really appreciate you
coming on the podcast thanks so much
this was this was a fun conversation
yeah it could go on for hours hopefully
the inside thank you
[Applause]
thanks for tuning in join us next time
on the AI native Dev brought to you by
Tesla
[Music]